Amina M. Roderick

Senior User Experience Designer

Get in touch by email

View my LinkedIn profile

I am a user-centered designer focusing on emerging ideas and technologies for over fifteen years. I believe that merging big picture goals with functional details is the best way to fulfill business objectives, delight users, and support brand experience.

Design Skills

- · Well-grounded in a structured approach informed by time constraints, design parameters, and the demands of multiple projects
- Demonstrated facility working independently, collaboratively, or in a supervisory role, during all phases of product development
- · Committed to a studied analysis, sustained by reclarification to maintain focus, culminating in a well articulated, simple design
- · Engaging leadership and discussions when running idea generation sessions and design reviews with multidisciplinary groups

Work Experience

User Experience Designer & Strategist, Co-owner

Designer Monster, LLC

Brattleboro, VT

2010 to Present

Responsible for bringing clients through the product development process by collecting requirements, understanding the target customer through user research, and designing for defined business goals

- · Advocate for the user while developing a design strategy, based on user testing, usability best practices, and client interviews
- · Collaborate with stakeholders to evaluate product requirements resulting in smartly designed products, apps, and software
- · Overhaul UX & UI to streamline usability of product and reinforce the client's brand, e.g. The Dinner Daily
- · Conceptualize and wireframe new applications for startups, e.g. Yarns

User Experience Design Manager

Dassault Systèmes I SolidWorks

Waltham, MA

2015 to 2019

Responsible for designing excellent user experiences for web and installed 3D CAD applications with multidisciplinary teams

- · Produced wireframes & mockups, performed user research, collaborated with developers and product managers
- · Carried out user testing and interviews to identify areas of design success and where further iterations required
- · Conceived new UI triad design to provide better understanding for user model in space; patent pending
- · Designed a user assistance learning tool to teach new users complex workflows; patent awarded
- Managed complete overhaul of the user experience and workflows for Sheet Metal app within new platform UI guidelines
- Presented three internal innovation awards for the *Design Guidance* feature and *xShape* application design

Industrial Designer

Osram Sylvania

Danvers, MA

2011 to 2014

Responsible for defining aesthetic direction and designing new line of indoor commercial LED lighting fixtures

- · Facilitated interaction & collaboration among multidisciplinary staff
- · Conceived, co-authored & co-presented six-part design and lighting workshop for change management initiative
- · Awarded three patents for inventive lighting designs; two LFI Innovation awards and a platinum award from the Design Journal

Industrial Designer

mmckenna → Humanscale

New York, NY

2006 to 2010

Responsible for supporting Niels Diffrient's ergonomic chair designs with 3D CAD models & photorealistic renderings; designing bleeding-edge LED lighting fixtures with modern aesthetics and manufacturability

- Successfully designed three NYC trade show booths per year with mmckenna; awarded Prominent New Booth
- · Launched Orchadia lighted sculpture, BettyLou lamp, & Element Task Light with distinguished press mentions and exhibits
- · Awarded patent for LED lighting design innovation at Humanscale; two Chicago Athenaeum awards & Best of NeoCon award

Product Designer

Lifetime Brands

Garden City, NY

2004 to 2006

Responsible for developing housewares concepts into functioning, manufacturable designs for mass production

- · Created 2D and 3D computer-generated renderings for proposed products
- Produced 2D drawings for price quotes & engineering production
- · Evaluated manufacturing samples for accuracy and acceptability to begin manufacturing

Education

Immersive Course in User Experience Design
September 2015 to November 2015General AssemblyBoston, MAMaster's in Industrial Design
2002 to 2004Rochester Institute of Technology
The College of WoosterRochester, NYBachelor's in English, Mathematics
1995 to 1999The College of WoosterWooster, OH

Organizations

Industrial Designers Society of America

2018 to present

Patents

Computer-Aided Interactive Learning April 2020	Dassault Systèmes I SolidWorks	10635461
Shaped Indirect Luminaire December 2016	Osram Sylvania	9528683
Linear Luminaire April 2016	Osram Sylvania	D754902
Virtual Surface Indirect Radiating Luminaire May 2015	Osram Sylvania	9022606
Lighting Apparatus and Method February 2014	Humanscale	864694
LED Based Lamp Replacement May 2013	Amina M. Chidiac	8441192